Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/santosh-penigalapati-3454a577 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

DevOps

Openshift

Red Hat Linux

Languages

English

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Administration

Santosh Penigalapati

DevOps & Cloud Engineer (Certified Specialist in OpenShift and AWS) at DBS

Singapore

Summary

DevOps (Certified Specialist in OpenShift and AWS) Engineer with a strong Linux and UNIX background.

Certifications:-

Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Administration AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Professional Summary:

Experience in Cloud infrastructure services Amazon Cloud and Google Cloud

Hands on experience in Docker containerization, Kubernetes,

OpenShift, Pivotal Cloud Foundry.

Experience in Platform automation through Shell script

Version Control Software : Subversion(SVN) and GIT Build/Script Tools : ANT, Maven and Shell Scripting

Application Servers : JBoss and WebLogic

Database: MySQL, MS SQL Server, Oracle9i/10g

Bug/Issue Tracking Tool : JIRA CI Tools : CloudBees Jenkins Code Analysis Tool : SonarQube

Deployment Tool: CA Release Automation

Public Cloud: AWS and GCP.

PaaS: OPENSHIFT and PIVOTAL CLOUD FOUNDARY (PCF)

Best Regards

Santosh P

+65 85713935

Email:- p.santosh2k4@gmail.com

Experience

DBS Bank
DevOps Engineer
August 2016 - Present (4 years 8 months)
Singapore

Sun Technologies System Specialist April 2013 - July 2016 (3 years 4 months) Bangalore , India

Tata Consultancy Services IT Analyst
May 2012 - April 2013 (1 year)

Handled Oracle Solaris, Linux, Aix, VXVM, VCS, ZFS and 3PAR Storage Technologies.

Worked for Ericsson

Develop, document, and maintain operational processes and tasks. Root Cause Analysis after Panic/Dump/Crash related to Solaris by coordinating with vendors as and when required.

Knowledge and hands on experience with administration of remote consoles Of Sun Hardware - ALOM/ILOM/System Controller/RSC

Taking care of the 4000+ Sun servers , 1500+ Linux Servers, and 1000+ AIX servers In critical production environment with 24/7 support.

Hewlett-Packard

Technical Consultant

February 2009 - January 2012 (3 years)

Handling Installation, configure and troubleshooting of Solaris & Linux.

Handled Nokia Unix Datacenter located in finland

Maintain service levels as per the established Service Level Agreements.

Decommission & commission of Solaris servers.

Up-gradation of Firmware of Linux & Solaris servers.

Administration of user management on Linux servers

Kernel Tuning and Patch Management.

IBM

Senior Operations Lead Specialist October 2008 - February 2009 (5 months)

Worked for Visteon client

Wipro

Server Management Engineer
December 2006 - October 2008 (1 year 11 months)

Mumbai Area, India and Bangalore

Worked as a Datacenter Engineer at Union Bank of India and Wipro datacenter.

Handled Solaris and Aix, servers

Accel Frontline Ltd
Customer Support Engineer
February 2006 - December 2006 (11 months)

Worked as residence engineer at Hindustan Times (Datacenter)
Provided FM (Facility Management) Support on Solaris and Linux

Education

Sri Venkateswara University
Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science · (2001 - 2004)